Coming to you live today from the first
voluntary mini camp practice of the Todd
Monken era here with Mason Graham.
Mason, first of all, good to see you,
man. Welcome back. How's the off season
treating you? It was good. Just, you
know, time away from the facility, but,
you know, it's good getting back in
here, seeing some new faces,
um and just, you know, starting the new
year. For you, this is kind of your
third year in a row with a different
staff. You go back to your last year at
Michigan, first year last year. What's
this one been like for you so far
getting to know Coach Ruttenburg and
obviously familiarity with Jack Cichy
there in your room? Yeah, I mean, it's
not too different for me, you know, I
got the same position coach. And then,
Coach Ruttenburg, you know, he's kind of
the same mindset, you know, he wants to
still attack and penetrate up front. So,
not much different for me, but um cool
seeing, you know, Coach Monken come in
and kind of, you know, set a new
standard here. Yeah, lots of team
periods today. I think that's going to
be kind of a hallmark. We're going to
get after play a lot of football. What
was it like being out there and actually
playing a little bit of football without
pads, obviously, but just out there
getting in the mix? Yeah, it was funny,
you know, last time we played some ball
with some of those guys was January. So,
you know, good getting out here, you
know, got some new faces, um
you know, just getting comfortable with
the guys again. What was the biggest
thing you learned in your rookie year?
Uh no, just like
I don't really know, honestly. Uh
if I had to say, you know,
take it takes a lot to, you know, win.
You know, it's hard to win in NFL. So,
you know, just kind of seeing how my
first year went and, you know, just how
I want things to change from what year
one to year two. What was something that
you liked about year one and what was
something that you went and took this
off season time down in Dallas to to
work on to to come back and improve here
in year two? Yeah, kind of just
reflecting on my season, you know, I
feel like I had a decent season, but
obviously not what I wanted, you know,
um
but just getting stronger was my main
focus.
Um just being more stout and
um you know, playing against against a
lot bigger guys and more experienced
guys. So, uh just strength was a big
thing for me. So, what did you do to
work on that down in Dallas? Cuz I
imagine you're stronger than just about
anybody else that you're going to
encounter on planet Earth. So, what's
like that kind of a program that you
went through this off season? Cuz you
look you look great.
>> Yeah, I appreciate it. But, uh just more
lifting stuff, but still keeping my
speed and agility. You know, that's
something I'm really good at is, you
know, my quickness and athleticism. So,
I already knew I kind of had that, but
just wanted to work on more of my
strength stuff that I needed to focus
on. What would you say it's been like
with Todd Monken so far? Cuz he's
putting his stamp on this football team,
not just from practice, I mean, just
even the meeting rooms. What's kind of
How would you describe kind of what his
his mission or his mindset that he wants
you guys to have is? Uh I would just say
urgent, you know, he wants to change
this, you know, place around, you know.
It's been like this for too long, you
know, we're trying to change this
around, you know. I've only been here
for one year and I'm already I'm already
tired of losing. So, trying to just turn
this around. Is that one of the harder
things that that people for people to
even comprehend from a psychological
standpoint is obviously Michigan, you're
national champion. Guys
losing two games in a year is like, "Oh
my goodness." Right? The NFL, as you
said, it's hard to win. Everybody is
very good in the NFL. The margin is very
small. Is that kind of one of the
interesting things to get your head
around? Yeah, I mean, it's just the
little things that can separate you from
winning or losing a game, you know. Feel
like guys in college, you can if you're
a way better team, you can make more
mistakes, get away with stuff, but, you
know, everyone's at the top of their
game. They're out there for a reason.
So, you got to be on top of your stuff.
And how excited are you for this season
and just getting back to work, getting
after it? Really excited. Um
just ready to win, you know, Coach
Monken keeps on
reiterating it, you know, just want to
win. We all want to win and just be a
part of something special. So,
Absolutely. Well, Mason, good to see you
again. Welcome back and let's go after
it. We're just day one here. We're just
laying a little foundation, long way to
go, but great to see you out there on
the grass today. Appreciate it.